- **\** 704-763-4832
- lynhmyle@gmail.com
- Culpeper, Virginia
- https://linkedin.com/in/lynh-casidy/
- % https://lynhcasidy.com
- % https://github.com/themother0fdogs

# SKILLS

- Web Development
  - o HTML
  - o CSS
  - JavaScript
  - Visual Studio Code
- Data Management / SQL
  - o MySQL
  - o SQLite
- Java
  - o Model-View-Controller Framework
  - o JavaFX Scene Builder
  - o IntelliJ IDEA
  - Android Studio
- C++
  - o Visual Studio Code
- UI/UX Design
  - o InVision Studio
  - o Adobe Photoshop
- Technical Communications

# EDUCATION

# B.S. Software Development

Western Governors University 2020-2023

# Diploma

King's College 2015-2015

#### Diploma

Highland School of Technology 2007-2011

# Additional education:

Shenandoah University (Nursing) 2017- 2018

University of North Carolina - Charlotte (Pre-nursing)
2013-2014

University of North Carolina – Greensboro (General)

2011-2012

# ABOUT ME

I recently graduated with my Bachelor's in Software Development at Western Governors University (WGU). While at WGU, I learned how to use SQL, Java, C++, and HTML/CSS. I have also learned the basics of data management, project management, foundations of scripting and programming, UI/UX design, and the foundations of network and security. Although I am new to the IT field, I will be a great addition to your team because I am goal-oriented, hardworking, and a quick learner. I am always willing to learn new things, as you can see by looking at my work experience and education history. Please check out my website and GitHub for all of the projects that I have worked on.

# EXPERIENCE

# Internet Safety & Quality Evaluator

Telus International / Remote / April 2019 - Present

The main purpose of my job at Telus is to evaluate content on multiple media platforms. I also assist with enhancing Al-powered products by improving search engines and training digital assistants to understand more languages and dialects.

#### Search engine optimization (SEO)

 To improve search engines, I would research search queries and compare them with the search results. This is to assure that the search results are yielding appropriate results when search requests are executed.

#### Quality control

 For quality control, I would review search results of a search query to determine if it is appropriate for the intended audience. My focus in these tasks is determining the suitability of media content for children under the age of 12.

# Al technology

 To enhance AI technology, I would examine user input for misspellings and languages to determine the possibilities of what the AI device's output would be.

# Veterinary Technician Assistant

PetCentre Animal Hospital / Manassas, Virginia/ January 2019-July 2020 My position here mostly consisted of assisting surgical veterinarians in surgeries, office appointments, and kennel work for boarded animals. This was my first experience working with animals.

#### Surgical

I would aid the veterinarians by setting up a sterile field and assisting them during surgery. I would monitor vitals while pets are under anesthesia. I would provide post-op care and discharge instructions for owners. For surgeries involving biopsies or fine needle aspirates, I would track the results and would give them to the veterinarian for review once I received results from pathology.

## Clinical

- I would do the basic clinical duties such as restraining pets, checking vitals, medication administration and dispensing, and utilizing IDEXX for the lab work that I acquired from pets. I also focused on providing client/patient education to help owners navigate the care of their pets.
- Occasionally, we will have unexpected emergencies, so I was required to think critically and quickly so I could provide appropriate care for pets.

# Lynh Casidy

#### Software Developer

- **\** 704-763-4832
- lynhmyle@gmail.com
- Culpeper, Virginia
- https://linkedin.com/in/lynh-casidy/
- % https://lynhcasidy.com
- % https://github.com/themother0fdogs

# CERTIFICATIONS

MTA: Software Development Fundamentals August 2020

CompTIA A+

November 2021 - November 2024

CompTIA Project+

June 2021 - June 2024

ITIL Foundations in IT Service Management
December 2021 - December 2024

## ORGANIZATIONS

National Technical Honor Society

Highland School of Technology

August 2010

Sigma Theta Tau International Honor Society of

Shenandoah University

November 2018

Women in Technology

Western Governors University

October 2020

# ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Chancellor's List

University of North Carolina - Charlotte
December 2014

Dean's List of Excellence

King's College

December 2015

Chancellor's List

Shenandoah University

December 2017

# EXPERIENCE

## **Medical Assistant**

Reston Breast Care Specialists / Reston, Virginia / February 2016 – December 2016

As a medical assistant, I assisted the doctors with appointments, surgical procedures, and assist with front office work.

#### Surgical

 I would aid the doctor by setting up a sterile field and assisting them during surgery. The doctor would extract cells using an ultrasound machine and my task involved preparing microscope slides and maintaining sterility.

#### Clinical

 On non-surgical days, I would set up appointments for the doctor by taking a patient's vitals, health history information, and reason for the visit.

#### Administrative

 I would work with radiology and pathology to schedule patients appropriately. I would assist the front office with answering phone calls and scheduling.

#### Medical Assistant Extern

Courtview Gynecology / Gastonia, North Carolina / October 2015 – December 2015

As an extern, I performed clinical functions and assisted doctors in sterile procedures. I also performed administrative functions. With this externship, I used my knowledge from school by applying it to every task in this externship.

#### Surgical

 My main surgical tasks were to maintain a sterile field while assisting the doctor during surgery. I worked with a team of medical assistants, and we would rotate surgery days.

#### Clinical

 I would set up appointments for doctors by taking the patient's vitals, health history information, and reason for visit. Along with setting up the appointment, I would aid the doctor in minor procedures by maintaining sterility, setting up microscope slides, and biopsy jars.

#### Administrative

 The office used a paper charting system and I assisted with the medical records department in organizing charts, pulling charts for the next day, and checking charts for pathology and radiology results.

# Children's Department Sales Associate

Dillard's / Gastonia, North Carolina / August 2013 – October 2015 I merchandised fashion, helped clients/customers with choosing outfits, and performed cash register duties.

#### Merchandising

 I maintained a neat and organized department, so customers have an easier time shopping. As a marketing strategy, I put together outfits for mannequins weekly to aid with the selling process of those items.

## Sales

 I had a sales quota that I had to meet monthly to retain my position in my department. I would maintain a clientele list for certain products in the store and would call them when new items arrive.